AHMAD ZAKI

J 37 Kalindi Kunj Road. New Delhi. 110025

Mobile: India +91 9999 324567 | Email: zakzakzaki@gmail.com

PROFILE

A strong academic background with a Masters in Media Management from the University of Westminster, London (Dissertation on IPTV, DTH and Telco) combined with significant senior level experience within electronic and digital media, sales and marketing sectors offering a well developed blend of analytical, problem solving, creative and technical skills. A strategic thinker with the ability to make quick and well judged proactive decisions. A thorough understanding of marketing and brand strategies, content development, commissioning, production, post production, acquisition for television shows, business development, marketing methods, models and theories as well as contemporary media practice. Strong commercial awareness and business acumen with a thorough understanding of revenue generation models and the ability to devise solutions to a wide range of commercial and organisational problems in a rapidly evolving and increasingly complex global media environment. Proven track record of developing long term sustainable and profitable relationships with high levels of client satisfaction and exceptional retention rates.

KEY SKILLS, EXPERIENCE AND KNOWLEDGE

Interpersonal & Communication
Marketing and brand strategies
Product Advrt/marketing (ATL & BTL)
IPTV/Telco marketing strategies
Market Research & Analysis
Budget management

Business Development
Content development/creation
Revenue generation strategies
Identifying new opportunities
Television broadcast code
TV Marketing

Website Content Management
PR, Social & Digital Media
External relationship management
Marketing through programming
Press Relations/Media Strategies
Brand Reputation Management

ENTREPRENEUR EXPERIENCE

ZakMedios (www.zakmedios.com) *Proprietor* March 2013 - Now

ZakMedios is a digital media and marketing agency offering a comprehensive suite of services designed to help clients gain maximum benefit and value from their marketing budget. ZakMedios helps clients across the globe raise their brand visibility and connect more effectively with customers. Its complete end to end package – from idea conceptualisation through to market launch – places it amongst a select few in India to provide a complete one stop shop solution. Recent clients include Asian Paints, Coca-Cola, French Embassy, Make in India by Arcelor Mittal, Sarens group, Muratech by Hero Motocorp, King Koil just to name few

- Overseeing the entire business from its operations to its marketing
- Managing the finances of the business and ensuring its profitability
- Generation of new business ideas and pitching to clients with tailor made proposals and associated quotes
- Working with media teams to produce videos, website content & development as well as TV commercials
- Writing and editing content scripts
- Building client databases and building sustainable relationships
- Development of new products and services to enhance offerings to clients

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, UK

Ekstasy (London) Ltd (www.ekstasy.co)

March 2011 - Dec 2011

Sales & Marketing Manager

Ekstasy Ltd is a global communications consultancy helping brands to simplify their communication needs and engage with their target audience using high quality video content. Clients include Land Rover, NHS, Sony, Canon, Cisco, Hilton Hotels, Ricoh, Radisson, Oberoi Hotels & Resorts. A member of the senior management team with key responsibility for ensuring the delivery of high quality and compliant content as well as overseeing and driving the successful implementation of sales strategies and tactical marketing programmes to support the organisations short and long-term growth and profitability objectives.

Key responsibilities include:

- Developing and implementing the marketing and sales plans and associated budgets
- Supervise all content development for the various clients.
- Generating revenue assessing potential, setting targets and delivering projections
- Identifying, evaluating and prioritising opportunities for business and relationship development with C-Level executives within target industry sectors
- Developing product innovation strategies to help guide the product development efforts and steer resource allocation and project selection
- Attending networking events such as exhibitions, trade show and seminars to generate B2B leads
- Monitoring and analysing market trends
- Monitoring the cost-efficiency and profitability of activity
- Leading a creative and dynamic sales and marketing team

Dream Merchants (London) Ltd (www.dreammerchants.biz)

July 2010 - Jan 2011

Manager, Marketing and Business Development

Increasing the overall efficiency of the company's services whilst also leading and overseeing the development and growth of profitable new business and securing contracts with new clients. Leading on the company's relationship with the media sector acting as a Business Growth Consultant for small and medium sized media organisations helping them to achieve growth through the development and implementation of effective growth strategies.

Key responsibilities include:

- Devising leadership development programmes and sound financial management systems for clients
- Developing strategies to exploit market opportunities
- Managing market research programmes to generate new ideas for brand development
- Designing innovative integrated sales and digital marketing campaigns
- Studying competitors' products and services
- Developing and managing a wide range of marketing techniques including traditional tools such as direct mail
 pieces and print advertising as well as a wide range of digital techniques including blogging, virals, websites,
 RSS feeds, SMS, podcasts and video emails

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE, INDIA (NDTV: 2000-2008)

New Delhi Television, (NDTV) www.ndtv.com

NDTV is a pioneer in India's news television boasting some of the most advanced production, news gathering and archiving facilities in South East Asia. It is today the most watched and the most respected news network in the country and is home to India's finest broadcast talent with award winning production and creative teams.

New Delhi Television Jan 2005 - Sept 2008

Producer (Reporting to Channel Head)

Overseeing the editorial content, production and presentation of NDTV news to the public.

Key responsibilities include:

- Supervising the overall content and flow of the programming and commercials
- Generating creative ideas for potential sponsorship and marketing deals for TV
- Ensuring high standards in the development, content writing and presentation of programme proposals
- Developing and executing plans for the digital marketing & sales team through programming content
- Conceptualising creative ideas and translating into business solutions
- Ensuring compliance with television broadcast code in the planning, scheduling and operation of programmes
- Managing a production team of Graphics Producer, CG Operator, Audio Manager, Donut Producer & Editor.
- Creatively supervise all content development for the channel from idea generation to broadcast execution

New Delhi Television Jan 2003 - Jan 2005

Reporter (Reporting to Input Head)

Reporting across all news areas for primetime television.

Key responsibilities include:

- · Reporting across a wide range of areas including lifestyle, entertainment, business, politics, current affairs and
- Evaluating news leads and tips for innovative story ideas
- Gathering and verifying factual information
- Script writing/ Content development and voice over
- Delivering breaking news from the event site or mobile broadcast unit

New Delhi Television Aug 2001 - Jan 2003

Weather Anchor (Reporting to Weather Head)

Delivering weather news on both NDTV India and NDTV Profit.

Key responsibilities include:

- Liaison with the meteorological office for the latest developments in national weather
- Creating 'extreme weather' reports including the provision of appropriate advice and guidance to viewers
- Recruiting new staff to the weather department
- Delivering functional and technical training to junior colleagues on 'iNEWS' software as well as script writing, screen presentation techniques and weather forecasting processes

Junior Transmission Controller (Reporting to Transmission Head)

Monitoring the quality and accuracy of on-air product, troubleshooting equipment malfunctions and preparing programming for playout.

Key responsibilities include:

- Updating control logs and maintaining audio and video transmissions of television programmes
- Scheduled equipment troubleshooting including on-air monitors and switching equipment
- Monitoring international affairs via global news agencies including APTN and Reuters

TECHNICAL SKILLS, EXPERIENCE, KNOWLEDGE AND LANGUAGES

- Technical knowledge of broadcasting transmission
- Key production tools and software including Avid NewsCutter, iNEWS, Omnibus and Columbus
- CMS (PHP)
- CRM software
- Telecom, IPTV and DTH related technology
- Microsoft Office
- Multilingual with fluency in English, Hindi, Urdu and basic Arabic reading skills.

EDUCATION

Masters in Media Management

University of Westminster, London. UK (Graduated with Merit)

Key projects included:

- · Management report on British Telco and Media company 'Virgin Media'
- Scenario planning The future of 'BskyB' (British Sky Broadcasting)
- · Content distribution strategies for various media platforms using marketing, sales and management tools
- Five year Business Plan for the development of an online social club
- Dissertation on IPTV and its competitors including DTH and cable TV

PG Diploma in Mass Communication & Journalism

Indira Gandhi National Open University, India

REFERENCES

References available upon request